# 我来了肯定咱也不能干啥
Since I am here, I need to do something.
# 今天咱来一个孜然羊肉
Today we will cook cumin lamb
# 这块肉可好
This piece of meat is really good
# 就这几个步骤掌握好了
If you control these few steps well
# 这盘菜成功率很高
the success rate of this dish will be high
# 选孜然羊肉 正常情况下
Normally, for the cumin seed lamb, you can choose
# 您使后腿肉或者使羊上脑肉都行
either leg or fillet.
# 我先把肉选出来好
I first pick the piece of lamb out.
# 这块肉不能用
We don't use this part.
# 这是正经八百吃涮肉最好的地儿了
This part is the best for hotpot
# 然后咱们这块从这儿开始
then we start cutting from this area
# 下一刀 这是羊的外脊
One more cut. This is the lamb loin.
# 这块留着涮肉去了
we save it for hotpot
# 然后后边那云皮给它蹬了
After that, let's peel off the skin on the back.
# 这个羊肉是当时 我跟一个忘年交（学的）
I learned this dish from a senior friend.
# 2002年的时候 这老爷子是乌鲁木齐的
Around 2002. My old buddy lives in Urumqi.
# 那时候我认识他的时候
When I first met him,
# 他就已经五十二岁了
he is alredy 52 years old
# 然后这个肉就选好了
Ok, we got the piece we want.
# 大家一定要把后边一层云皮蹬了
Guys you must peel off the skin backside
# 这个菜咱们平常去店里边去吃
This dish, we often have in the restaurants,
# 他买羊肉都是切成片
They usually slice the lamb.
# 实际上孜然羊肉应该是切成粒
Actually,  cumin lamb should be cut in cubes.
# 实际上这个肉不是撑盘的菜 是要口感的菜
since the meat in this dishes is not for presentation, but for texture.
# 我们这老大哥教的时候
When the old buddy teached me
# 他说你这必须要切成粒 要不然没口感
He said you must cut the lamb into cubes
# 它这肉里边有纹 看见了么
See, there are some marble fat inside of the meat.
# 这个肉 做孜然羊肉是口感最好的了
This part is the best for cumin lamb.
# 比纯瘦的好吃
better than lean meat
# 这么多够了吧大爷 不少
Is that enough, Da Ye? It is quite a lot.
# 咱打一鲜姜汁
let's make some ginger juice.
# 来一点点水
add some water
# 粉碎机
blender
# 这个菜 关键点就在这
the key for this dish is here
# 鲜姜汁进去就压下羊肉的膻味
fresh ginger juice can cover the gamy flavor
# 然后提一下羊肉的香味
then the meaty smell will appear
# 咱这姜汁儿进去了 来一勺盐
after we add the ginger juice, put a spoon of salt
# 这盐得底口稍微足一点
we need add enough salt at the beginning
# 胡椒粉 白胡椒
pepper which is white pepper
# 这都是在腌羊肉里边必须的
these are all the must-have ingredients for marinating the lamb
# 搅拌均匀  别使太大的劲
mix evenly, but do not stir too hard
# 因为咱这肉块让它整点
because we want the lamb to be complete
# 然后咱们来一点点的酱油
then, let's add some soy sauce
# 最好黄豆酱油 味道还挺浓
better to use soybean soy sauce. It has strong flavor.
# 这里边不要加鸡蛋
do not put egg
# 直接上干粉 玉米淀粉
use the corn startch to cover it
# 这淀粉不要太大
we dont need too much
# 也是抄拌 拌匀了它就行了
still stirring it. After fully mix, it is done
# 其实这淀粉是锁住原料的水分
actually this corn startch is used for locking the water inside the ingredients
# 另外增加原料的嫩度
additionally to keep its tenderness
# 还有起到了一个外焦里嫩的脆感
make its crust crispy with tender inside
# 待会儿滑肉的时候油温稍微高一点
When we stir the lamb cubes, the oil temperature should be a bit high
# 比咱们滑肉的时候要高
higher than usual
# 拌点油 封住
put some oil , lock it up
# 这油可以大一点 没事
We can use a large amount of oil. It's fine
# 一会还回到油锅里头 一点不浪费
later we pour back to the oil pot which means no waste
# 别人的香菜都是切成段直接码盘底下
Others cut cilantro into peices then just put it on the bottom of the plate
# 当时我们老哥哥说你这个香菜
My old buddy taught me that the cilantro
# 只有把叶子给它搁到盘底下行
you can only put the leave on the bottom.
# 因为它直接羊肉一腾它就熟了
because it will be cooked after you put the lamb on top.
# 这个梗一定要下锅
stems also need to be used
# 它是什么 给它切成粒
what do we need to do with it? Chop it into small dices.
# 你看同样做羊肉 同样做孜然羊肉
See, people make the same dish, make the cumin lamb
# 每个人的手法都不一样
but people cook differently
# 今天我看到亮子这个手法还是挺新鲜的
today i found it is novel to see Liangzi's method.
# 你看他用的全是叶
you see, all he used are leaves
# 洋葱芯不要 咱们要它这个瓤
onion pulp, don't need. We need the outer layers
# 就是外边这层皮儿 芯儿太嫩
It is the external skin. The pulp is too tender
# 孜然 千万不要用孜然粉
cumin. Don't use the powder
# 孜然粉吃着到时候它糊嘴
Cumin powder will stick on your month.
# 咱们要孜然粒 吃它那香
we need the cumin seeds. It is aromatic.
# 小火煸炒就行
use low heat to stir up.
# 大爷香味出来了 很酥了 差不多了
Da Ye, it becomes aromatic, seems like crispy, should be done.
# 再炒就过火了 正合适
If we stir a bit longer, it will be too much. Now is about right.
# 辣椒面要细辣椒面 香啊
chili powder, we need the finely grinded one. smells good.
# 干炒也是 就是给它焙一下
also need to fry it without oil, just heat it up.
# 因为把那生辣椒味给它焙出去
just get rid of raw chili flavor
# 要辣椒的香
we only need the aroma
# 咱们起锅烧上油
let's start cooking, add the oil
# 我做肉菜比较费油
I need a lot of oil when I make meat dishes.
# 因为有时候这东西少了油它却确实不行
since sometimes the meat is truely not so good without the oil
# 现在咱把肉一滑基本上就能吃了
now the lamb just need to be slightly fry and it can be eaten.
# 它就这几味料
only need a few condiments
# 实际上羊肉这东西料不需要太多
actually dont need too much condiments for lamb
# 吃羊肉的本味和鲜味
just taste the ordinary smell and umami.
# 网友要在家做 就这几个步骤掌握好了
if you guys wanna cook at home, just know these steps well
# 这盘菜成功率很高
easy to success.
# 这个放进去别着急动
put this inside, dont hurry to touch it
# 因为咱们肉浆的时候 这粉子上的就合适
Because we added the right amount of starch.
# 不用复油炸 不用
Don't need to fry the second time? no
# 这个也不能把它的水分炸的太干
we shouldn't fry it for too long to loose its moisture.
# 因为太干了到时候没口感了
if it is too dry,  it will not have the right texture.
# 这就差不多了
here we go
# 搁盆里头
put into the pot
# 油温让它高一点 一次成型
Heat up the oil temperature, so we make it one-shot
# 这比第一锅炸的酥
more crispy than the first pot
# 为什么 因为量合适了
you know why , because the amount is right.
# 这个看到了吧 就让它外边
see it, just keep it outside
# 有点焦焦的小边
outside a bit burnt
# 但是还不能说是脆的
but it still can't be crispy.
# 因为它要外焦里嫩这焦是边上的焦
becuase it needs tender with a crispy crust, the crispy crust is the burnt parts on the edge.
# 里边还是嫩的 这就行了
inside is still tender, that's enough
# 实际上这个连调味都不用调
In fact, we don't even need seasoning
# 这主要就是腌底口的时候调好了
It is because the flavor is set during the marination.
# 一次就成了
one-shot
# 这个葱一定要给它爆香
the onion need to be fry till fragrant.
# 这时候香味一出来 来点酱油
after the aroma come out, add some soy sauce
# 羊肉 翻炒
stir fry the lamb
# 小锅翻的
Look his techniques!
# 孜然粒 撒进去
Add the cumin seeds
# 您爱吃孜然咱就多来一点
If you like cumin, you can add more
# 一定要让它粒粒都粘上孜然
let every cube dip with the cumin seeds
# 还可以撒点芝麻
also can add some sesame
# 辣椒面 喜欢吃辣的你也可以多来
chili power, can put more if you like
# 这个香菜梗 这是点睛之笔
the cilantro stems, this is the key
# 叫什么神笔马良 画龙点睛之笔
which is called the finishing touch
# 一定要让它孜然粒匀匀的粘在肉上
must let the seeds evenly attached on the cubes
# 看着就香 闻着就香
looks nice, smell also nice
# 二伯先吃 我拍您
Er Bai you eat first, i take shot of you
# 肯定是先给大爷吃 您离我远点
Surely, Da Ye need to get the first bite. Please stand a bit away
# 您先吃师父 奖励奖励
Master you eat first. It is the reward.
# 我刚才偷着吃半天了
i have secretly eaten a long time.
# 我来一武吃的你看着大爷
i just grab it
# 这个口感跟片儿绝对截然不同
this texture is truly different from the sliced style
# 而且它的配料简单
and the ingredients are simple
# 而且它搭配的四种料的搭配最强
the four condiments' combination is the best
# 现在最关键是什么
now what's the key
# 是这孜然粒你嚼到嘴里边咯吱咯吱香
it's the aroma in your mouth, when you chewing the cumin.
# 一定要吃这个孜然粒的香
the aroma of the cumin seed is the key.
# 腌料足 姜汁打的好 去膻
The marinade is great, the ginger juice is good. It gets rid of the gamy flavor.
# 这味儿一次性加足
Add enough flavoring in one-shot.
# 还有一个重要的在哪
another point is
# 孜然和辣椒面是炒的 干炒之后干焙
the cumin seeds and chili powder are fried. toast it after frying.
# 焙的火候恰到好处
The degree of toasting is about right.
# 香味一下激发出来
it brings out the aroma
# 我就说最后一个感受
i just say my last feeling
# 今天我吃的这盘孜然羊肉是最好的
today this cumin lamb is the best
# 别的都不好吃
better than others
# 我乌鲁木齐的老大哥要听见 他得多高兴
if my old buddy from Urumqi heard this, he will be very happy
# shift forward 00:07:41,800
# 问二伯平时吃什么东西能够防脱发
Er Bai, what does you eat usually to prevent hair loss?
# 其实和自己的生活习惯有关系
actually it is related to your living style.
# 第一
first
# 好的心态这是最关键的东西
healthy mindset is the key
# 还有一样
another
# 千万别熬夜
do not stay up too late
# 多吃一些黑的东西
eat more dark colour food
# 豆类啊 五谷啊
like beans and whole grains
# 芝麻啊 什么黑豆啊这些黑东西
sesame and black beans these kinds of black colour food
# 特别是桑葚
specially the mulberry
# 我们可以用山楂 荷叶 决明子冲水喝
We can drink water with Chinese hawthorn, lotus leaf, cassia seeds
# 其实您都不知道 网友都说您这头发是假的
you might not know, some people say your hair is fake
# 好多人都说您这头发做发型了
many of them say you make hairstyle
# 没有没有
Absolutely not
# 还有一个
still have one more
# 基本我每天洗澡的时候挠这个头发
I scratch my head almost everyday when i shower
# 基本一百七到二百下
170 to 200 times
# 梳头 梳理呀
Comb my hair from time to time